CECIL E. KING

1268 Foxglove Place, Mississauga, ON, L5V2N3 Email: cek333@yahoo.com | Phone: 647-238-4395

Portfolio: https://cek333.github.io/Responsive Portfolio/portfolio.html

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cecil-e-king/ | Github: https://github.com/cek333

SUMMARY

I'm a full stack web developer with a background in ASIC verification. In Dec 2020, I obtained a certificate in web development from the UofT SCS Coding bootcamp. At the bootcamp, I worked individually and in teams to construct applications utilizing the full MERN stack (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, React, and Node.js). As a verification engineer, I developed tests, troubleshooted failures, and collaborated with globally dispersed team members, thereby sharpening my debugging and written communication skills. I'm also detailed-oriented, a quick learner, and I relish the opportunity to solve problems with creative solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, jQuery, C, Perl, SystemVerilog **Databases:** MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React

Backend: Node.js, Express, Handlebars, REST APIs

Version Control: Git, Github, CVS, Mercurial

Deployment: Heroku

PROJECTS

Reading List: Full stack app to search for and save books of interest.

- Github: https://github.com/cek333/Reading List
- Deployed: https://reading-list-45753.herokuapp.com/
- Technologies Used: MERN (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, React, Node.js), Bootstrap

Eat-Da-Burger: Full stack app to add and update lists of burgers.

- Github: https://github.com/cek333/Eat-Da-Burger
- Deployed: https://radiant-basin-63106.herokuapp.com/
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MySQL

E-logical Trivia: Trivia Quiz App. Bootcamp group project.

- Github: https://github.com/FarhinChowdhury/Trivia-Quiz
- Deployed: https://e-logical-trivia-20809.herokuapp.com/
- Technologies Used: MERN (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, React, Node.js), Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

Senior Engineer, Hardware: Pixelworks, Toronto, Ontario (Aug 2017 - Aug 2020)

- Generated clean regression reports pre-tapeout with over 95% branch and statement coverage by:
 - Running the IP and full-chip simulations and generating the regression and coverage reports
 - Notifying the IP designers of any issues and verifying the fixes
 - Writing test plans and tests, and maintaining testbenches for IPs in the Iris product line using the object-oriented Universal Verification Methodology (UVM)
- Supported successful functional and performance verification on the prototyping systems by partitioning the RTL design across multiple FPGAs using Synopsys' Certify

Senior Engineer, HW Emulation: Vixs Systems, Toronto, Ontario (Nov 2010 - Aug 2017) Engineer, ASIC Engineering, HW Emulation: Vixs Systems (Jul 2007 - Nov 2010) System Verification Engineer: Vixs Systems (May 2004 - Jul 2007)

- Worked on the verification of the company's ASIC designs, enabling first-pass silicon success on tapeout by:
 - Maintaining in-house and third-party FPGA prototyping systems used for the verification of XCode products
 - Partitioning the RTL design across multiple FPGAs using in-house and third-party tools
 - Developing and maintaining synthesis and place and route scripts that transformed the RTL into programmable bitfiles for testing on the prototyping systems
 - Debugging and resolving place and route issues
 - Writing tests for some of the XCode IPs (Transport Stream Demux, Smartcard)
 - Assisting with the maintenance of the full verification test suite
 - Troubleshooting regression failures.
- Contributed to the successful launch of many of our customers' products by assisting the Field Application Engineers with debugging product issues

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies (Sep - Dec 2020)

 Three month ramp up on the technologies and skills necessary for full stack web development.

Certificate, Computer Security and Digital Forensics: Ryerson University - G. Raymond Chang School of Continuing Education (2014 - 2017)

Program Covered: Computer Network Security, Cryptography, Digital Forensics
Systems, Security Architecture and Design, CISSP (Prep), and a Capstone Project.

Bachelor of Applied Science, Computer Engineering: University of Toronto (1999 - 2004)